剧情回顾
Previously on sanctuary...
我发誓我会让你幸福的，Helen
I promise to make you happy, Helen,
至死不渝
For all eternity.
John，让我帮帮你吧，免得事态更加恶化
John, let me help you before you make things worse.
还会更糟吗？
And how is that possible?
我已经杀掉有…七个妓女了？
I've already murdered, what, seven whores?
真是不可思议
[Will]: it's amazing to me,
开膛手杰克、夏洛克・福尔摩斯，你俩居然能坐到一起…
Jack the Ripper, Sherlock Holmes, The fact that you two can sit here together...
时间能治愈一切
Time is a great healer.
赎罪，可就没这么简单了
Redemption, that requires a little more.
护盾工作正常，如果是他的话，我们很安全
The shield is working. If it's him, we're safe.
那是改进的电磁泡
[Henry]: It's a modified em bubble.
保护我们免受外界干扰
It protects outside interference from jamming devices.
她是这么跟你说的？
[Druitt]: Is that what she told you it was for?
那它是做什么的？
[Henry]: What is it for?
防我的
Me.
你妈妈见死不救确实差点让我归西
[Druitt]: Your mother did indeed leave me close to death.
原谅我，John
Forgive me, John.
Tesla找到并治好了我
[Druitt]: Tesla found me, revived me,
曾驱使我杀戮的怒火已经熄灭了
And the rage that once fueled me is gone.
Tesla或许折磨你到求生不得，John
Tesla may have shocked you into your senses, John,
但若无杀戮欲，谁也不会变成你那样
But nobody becomes what you were without a predilection for killing.
早晚你必会恢复嗜杀本性
No doubt you'd return to your murderous habits one day.
我并非邀你去约会
I wasn't asking you out on a date.
还有哪儿疼吗？
谢谢
你做的很好
You're doing a great job.
祖鲁语中，“一切都会好的”要怎么说？
Um, how do you say, "it's all going to be okay" in zulu?
就像她说的
What she said.
没错，尽量放松
That's right, keep it light.
他们已经受惊过度，不需要消极影响了
They're already panicked enough without picking up on our fears.
记着，他们是“神入者”，能察觉你的感受
(ss:大概就像被《银河系漫游指南》里的“立场转换枪”打中)
Remember, they're empaths. They feel what you're feeling.
新霉素？
Neomycin?
嗯，一对遇难者夫妇有二级烧伤
Yeah, a couple of the intakes have second-degree burns.
你联系孟买庇护所了吗？
Did you contact the mumbai sanctuary?
已经告知他们神入者没事
Told them the empaths are safe.
至于船嘛…
Their ship, on the other hand...
怎么样了？
How's it looking?
嗯，不妙啊
Yeah, not so good.
席琳迪翁该一展歌喉了
(ss:Celine Dion，电影《泰坦尼克号》主题曲演唱者)
Celine Dion should start singing about now.
抱歉拿灾难开玩笑，并不好笑
Sorry. Disaster joke, not funny.
他被什么拖住了？
What the hell is keeping him?
火势蔓延开了，到处都是浓烟！
Fire's spreading, smoke everywhere!
别担心，你安全了
没事了，跟我来
It's okay, just come with me.
其余船员呢？
The rest of the crew?
死了
Dead.
Musa！她还在船上
还有一个神入者没找到
One of the empaths is still missing.
休息室查了吗？
Did you check the sleeping quarters?
具体状况不明，贸然跳过去可能被困住
Without detailed knowledge of the vessel, Arrivals can be tricky.
我要知道去哪儿才行
I need a known destination--
是
Yes.
走了
On my way.
只要…小心点
Just--Be careful.
Henry，知道船出什么事了吗？
Henry, any idea what happened to the ship?
最佳推测，从马普托出发后两小时，锅炉爆炸
(ss:马普托，莫桑比克首都)
Best guess? About two hours out of maputo, the boiler exploded,
船体被撕开一个大洞
Tore a hole in the hull.
好吧
All right.
你可能要帮忙包扎下新伤患
I may need your help bandaging the new intakes.
啊，得了吧，博士
Aw, yeah, come on, doc.
你知道我见不得血
You know about me and blood.
好吧，那就收拾下客房
All right, get the guest quarters ready.
今晚要多加几张床了
We're going to need a few extra beds tonight.
收到
Check.
她腹部被金属碎片击中
Metal fragment in her abdomen!
天呐，脉搏很微弱
Dear god, her pulse is weak.
带她到手术室
Get her to the o.R.
我要马上做手术
I need to operate immediately.
John？
John?
今天真够受的
It's quite a day.
多亏你肯帮忙
Thank you for answering my call.
看来咱俩的事永远没完
It seems business is never finished with us,
尽管失去的也不少
Despite our losses.
我只是说，这事没你完不成
I'm just saying, I couldn't have done it without you.
同舟共济，是吧？
Well, all hands on deck, hmm?
此外，我很怀念这里
Besides, I've missed this place.
手刃仇敌固然大快人心，但…
You know, vengeful killing sprees are good for the soul, but...
回家的感觉更好
There's no place like home.
今天传送的次数还真多
Quite a lot of teleportation for one day.
有没有哪里不舒服？
You feeling any worse for wear?
完全正常
Right as rain.
实际上，感觉再好不过了
In fact, I've...I've never felt better.
――――――――――――――――――
syjhsh翻译, 不当之处请多见谅
本字幕制作纯属个人兴趣
仅供学习交流, 严禁用于商业用途
――――――――――――――――――
异形庇护所 第二季 第11集
没有John帮忙的话，他们的处境真是不堪设想
I can't imagine what would have happened to them had John not answered my call.
“闹鬼”
附近没有任何救难船只
There was no rescue craft close enough to have saved any of them.
幸运啊
Lucky.
的确
That she is.
这东西再靠右1厘米就切到降主动脉了
One more centimeter to the right, And this would have lacerated her descending aorta.
心跳停止
Cardiac arrest.
该死！推过车来！
Dammit! Get the cart!
1毫克肾上腺素
One milligram epinephrine.
救活了
Alive.
暂时的
For now.
她仍然没脱离危险期
She's not out of the woods yet.
先缝合伤口吧
Let's close her up.
喂，哥们，Kate要你帮忙搞定遇难者数据库
Hey, man, Kate needs your help with the intake database.
你做不了？
Can't you do it?
我试过，不过看来系统已经瘫痪
I tried, but it looks like the system's fried.
嘿，我正忙着呢
Hey, I'm a little busy here.
哇…
Whoa...
你去跟孟买那边说吧
Look, tell that to mumbai.
他们一直吵着要我们尽快帮忙恢复日志
They're screaming for our rescue and recovery logs asap.
Molly需要预充电
Molly's primed for a charge.
我目前还不能为她打包票
I can't exactly bail on her right now.
Molly？
Molly?
“改进O波线性发射器”首字母缩拼词
Modified o-wave linear expeller.
那该叫做“mole”吧 (ss:mole, 鼹鼠)
Doesn't that acronym spell "mole"?
Molly更热辣
Molly's hotter.
哥们，这是武器，不是美女
Dude, it's a weapon, not a woman.
嘿，显然咱俩的品味不同
Hey, clearly you and I have not dated the same girls.
OK，你到底要不要去，因为…
Okay, look, are you going to do this thing, Because--
OK，好，是，好
Okay, fine. Yes. Fine.
那你要在这替我一会儿，OK？
You're going to have to take over for me, okay?
Molly需要先充电、再组合，然后装填脉冲弹
Molly needs to be charged and assembled before the seams on the pulse magazine degrade.
哇，你刚刚胡编的吧？我完全听不懂
Whoa, you just made that up, right? That means nothing to me.
你只要打开主仓
All you got to do is open the stock,
取出能量源并充电
Remove the power core and charge it,
然后重新装回能量源
Then you re-insert the power core back into the stock,
装填弹药，拉开主轴
You seal the magazine, vent the shaft,
固定激光瞄准器
Secure the laser sight,
搞定
And presto.
你早知道我连内六角扳手都用不好，是吧？
You realize you're talking to a guy who flunked allen key, right?
放松，没问题的
Relax. You'll be fine.
哦，能量源不要充电过度
Oh, don't overcharge the power core.
否则会炸掉实验室
You'll blow up the lab.
OK，那就没什么好担心的了
Okay, so no pressure, then.
谢谢你救了我们，你真是个圣人
不客气
You're welcome.
为何如此悲伤
我跟你们没感情
I feel nothing for you people.
只是帮个忙、完成任务而已
It was a favor, a task, nothing more.
如果一直被黑暗左右，这里永远不会成为你的家
你说什么？
What did you say?
拜托…不要…我不是那个意思…
我劝你最好别取笑我
I urge you not to trifle with me.
你该保持沉默的
You should have said nothing.
你不该打扰我的
You should have left well enough alone.
为什么要来烦我？
Why did you come to me?
现在全靠她自己了
It's up to her now.
能做的我们都做了
We've done all we can.
推到医务室调养？
Recovery in the infirmary?
伤情稳定前要实时监控
I want her monitored until she's stable.
今天本会更糟的
Today could have gone a lot worse than it did.
原来你在这儿，有点不对劲
抱歉，我不懂祖鲁语
Oh, I'm sorry. I don't speak zulu.
Nozipho失踪了
她不在这儿，不在这儿
Nozipho，另一个神入者
Nozipho, one of the other empaths.
不在这儿
就像你一样
She's like you.
你没…没…
You can't- you can't--
失踪了…
你没看到她
You can't see her.
她在庇护所里迷路了？
Is she lost in the sanctuary?
她…
天啊，抱歉，我听不懂
Oh, god, I'm so sorry, I don't understand.
你无法…无法…
You can't... You can't...
你无法…
You can't...
你无法感觉到她
You can't sense her anymore.
遇到麻烦了
哦，OK，跟我来
Oh, okay. Come with me.
你是怎么弄的？
What did you do to this thing?
哦，得了，变成我的错了？
Oh, come on, so now it's my fault?
我只是说，看到这儿了吗？
Well, I'm just saying, you see this?
数据库是谁设计的？
Who designed the database?
不是数据库的问题
It is not the database.
嗯，你才不会承认
Yeah, says you.
你…
Are you...
这是谁干的？
Who does this?
怎么了？
What?
OK，这是什么？
Okay, what is this?
我用了下电脑
I use my computer.
那这是什么？
What is this?
啊，the craven throng？
Ah, the craven throng?
实验酸车库风格
It's experimental garage acid.
得了吧，你是说我的音乐破坏了数据库
Oh, come on, you're telling me that my music screwed up your database?
你的免费播放器强行入网，导致了端口冲突
Your freeware media player created a conflict in the com port access.
怎么你一开口，我就只听到废话…废话…废话…？
Why is it whenever you talk, all I hear is, "blah, blah, blah, blah?"
这不是你的个人音响系统，OK？
I did not create this to be your personal stereo system, okay?
我…
I...
那是…
Is that...
哇！
Whoa!
哦…
Oh...
血仍未冷
Blood's fresh,
20或30分钟前遇害
20, maybe 30 minutes.
喉咙被切开
Her throat's been cut.
Henry，去查监控录像
Henry, get the security camera footage.
看半小时内谁到过这层
I want to know everyone who was on this floor in the last half hour.
好的
All right, you got it.
Kate，把客人们集合起来
Kate, gather our guests.
我搞不懂
I don't get it.
这帮家伙那么友善，没威胁到谁啊
These guys are so gentle. They're no threat to anybody.
确实
Exactly.
就像是待宰羔羊
They're the perfect target.
很漂亮…
Beautiful...
不是吗？
Isn't it?
转过身来
Turn around
要慢慢的
Very slowly.
(又开始嗜杀)多久了？
How long?
很久了
Long enough.
本性…难移
Habits are... Hard to break.
或许你没尽力克制
Perhaps you're not trying hard enough.
我就是这样
I am who I am.
你早该有防备的
It's high time you did something about it.
John！
John!
这么说电磁护盾也开了吧
I take it the em shields are up.
不错
Indeed.
博士！我听到枪声了
Doc! I heard shots.
Kate！
Kate!
(ss:一个路口，俩人被放倒，)
他…
Is he...
他死了
He's dead.
再重复下为何要尽力救活杀人狂
Tell me again why you're trying to bring a homicidal maniac back to life.
关键是起因
It's more about compulsion than murder.
纵容他向Cabal复仇，是我让他重蹈覆辙的
I set him up for this, letting him loose on the Cabal.
他知道早晚会被我发现
He knew I'd find out about his activities sooner or later.
他想让我动手杀他
He wanted me to kill him.
无意冒犯，不过你们的关系可真够乱的
No offense, but you guys got a seriously messed-up relationship.
这很复杂
It's complicated.
除颤器充电
Charge the defibrillator.
第二档设到200
Second button there to 200,
准备！
And clear!
没反应
Nothing.
准备！
Clear!
哦，怎么搞的？
Oh, what the hell?
Henry，我在楼下，电灯闪得厉害
[will]: Uh, Henry? I'm downstairs. The lights are flickering.
嗯，我知道
Yeah, I know, I know.
电压激增
We took a power surge.
他有呼吸了
He's breathing again.
医务室，有麻烦了
The infirmary. We got a problem.
还在吸氧的神入者，Musa
The empath on oxygen, Musa.
她那没信号了，我们得把她带过来，Will…
She's gone offline. We have to get her back here. Will...
立刻把医务室的病人带到手术室
Bring the patient from the infirmary to the o.R. Now.
了解
On it.
博士，我要重启主系统
Doc, I need to do a major system reboot.
医疗分机也会有几纳秒异常
Can you live without your med servers for a few nanoseconds?
好的
Do it.
我们要检查下异形隔离系统是否有漏洞
We need to check for any breaches in abnormal containment.
全面安检要等Henry重启完毕后
We won't have full security until Henry's reboot is complete.
跟开膛手杰克独处，你没问题吧？
Y-you're cool hanging with jack the ripper?
他现在人畜无害
He's no danger to anyone right now.
Helen…
Helen...
不知为什么…
I don't know why...
我感觉好奇怪
I feel so strange.
我还不想这么快结束
I know you wanted this to end more quickly.
抱歉让你失望了
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
为什么要救活我？
Why did you bring me back?
主机重新上线
Main server's coming back online now.
我这就去手术室复查设备
I'm going to head to the o.R. And check on the bio-techs.
保持联系
Keep me posted.
电磁护盾全功率运行
The em shield is at full strength.
你如果传送逃跑，必死无疑
Attempt to teleport, and you will die.
我明白
I understand.
这是我的错，John
This is my fault, John.
我不该相信你能改过自新
I should never have believed that you could change, that you had changed.
你又杀了几人？自从…
How many have there been since...
自从重返庇护所？
Since you let me back in?
那还重要吗？
Does it matter?
你又开始杀戮了，杀的还不止Cabal余党
You've been killing again, and not just Cabal remnants.
我为控制自己所做的努力，也都不重要了吧
Does it matter that I never wanted it to begin again, that I tried to stop?
Helen，我尽力了
Helen, I tried.
白教堂的事又重演了
(ss:历史上开膛手杰克的杀人地点在伦敦东区白教堂一带)
This is s whitechapel all over again.
你会好起来的
You're going to be okay.
你会好起来的，我要带你去手术室
You're going to be okay. I'm going to get you to the o.R.
拜托，庇护所里有什么东西
肺部有些不舒服，但你会好起来的
Your lungs are hurt, but you're going to be okay.
庇护所里有很可怕的东西
拜托，我们必须撤离，必须撤离
你会好起来的，你要戴上这个
It's going to be okay. You need to put this on.
抱歉，我听不懂你说的
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
抱歉，我会带你去Magnus博士那儿，她能听懂你的话
I'm sorry. I'll get you to dr. Magnus. She'll understand you.
一切都会好的，OK？我们要出发了
You're going to be fine, okay? I'm going to get you going.
我不懂祖鲁语，抱歉
I don't speak any zulu, I'm sorry.
那么，我说的对吗？
So was I right?
你想老板是不是对要命的高光头一直余情未了？
You think the boss still has the hots for tall, bald and deadly?
伙计，我还以为我有人际关系问题
Man, I thought I had relationship issues.
你呢，大个子？有没有对你很特殊的人？
What about you, big guy? Anyone special in your life?
我每五年繁殖一次
I mate every five years.
跟谁？
With who?
喂，到底怎么了？谁在同时用微波炉和烤箱？
Hey, what the hell happened? Someone plug the microwave and the toaster in at the same time?
你难倒我了
You got me.
我还在试着修复系统
I'm still trying to get all systems back online.
她怎么样？
How's she doing?
维生装置烧毁了
Her life support is fried.
正在用后备的
She's on back-up.
Magnus想时刻注意她的状况
Magnus wants to keep her close.
好啊，我们是后备的，竭尽全力干吧
All right, we are back up and firing on all cylinders.
那么，先说说这儿谁最厉害？
Now, tell me, who's your daddy?
我去看下其他的病人
I'm going to go check on the other patients.
怎么？
What?
我会安排你转移到国外更保险的地方
I'm arranging for your transfer to a secure facility out of the country.
你太过危险，不能再重获自由了
You are far too dangerous to ever be free again.
又怎么了？
What happened now?
停了
Stopped.
太棒了
Great.
这么严重？
Seriously?
喂！
Hello!
我知道，我知道
I know, I know,
自动封闭程序启动了！
We're in auto lockdown!
我正试着撤销它
I'm getting an override going now.
哦，得了吧！
Oh, come on!
Will，情况不妙
Will, this is not good--
Henry
Henry.
哦，伙计
Oh, man.
OK
Okay, uh...
她叫什么来着？
What was her name again?
Magnus说的好像是…Bosa
Magnus said something like... Bosa.
嗯…Musa！
Mm, antlers... Musa!
Musa！Musa，OK
Musa! Musa, okay.
安慰一下让她镇定下来
So just talk to her and calm her down.
这很重要
It's very important.
OK
Okay.
嘿，Musa…
Uh, hey, Musa...
嗨
Hi.
搞什么？没信号？什么时候开始的？
What? No signal? Since when?
被什么干扰了
Something's jamming it.
啊，真该死
Aw, come on.
啊，我快被逼疯了
Agh, this is nuts.
不要再按了
Stop doing that.
你们都不更新保险装置吗？
Don't you guys update your safety equipment?
经常更新
Constantly.
是吗，那为什么都失灵了？
Yeah, well, then, why isn't anything working?
怎么没听到那个鬼魂似的声音“冷静，救援马上到”？
Where's the disembodied voice saying, "chill out. Help's coming?"
那是我的声音
I'm that voice.
会有救援吗？
Is help coming?
不会
No.
不该这样的
This shouldn't be happening.
喂，从这顶上能爬到另一层吗？
Hey, can we go out the top, climb up to the next floor?
可以，但不要那么做，不安全
Yes, we can, but we're not going to. Not safe.
OK，大个个
Okay, biggie,
《Speaking In Code》的那套对我可没用
(ss:Kate以为猿人大叔搞坏电梯想亲近她-_-b)
This whole speaking-in-code thing is really not working for me.
什么地方出问题了，没搞清前不要轻举妄动
Something's wrong. Need to know what before we do anything rash.
嗯，确实不该那样
Yeah, wouldn't want to do that.
那是个老式无线电盒子
That is some old-school radio shack.
是最初的电话系统吗？
Is that an original phone system?
这部分建好时装的
From when this wing was built.
看来几十年没用过了
Looks like it hasn't been used in years.
是的
It hasn't.
你觉得还能用吗？
Do you really think it's going to work?
如果你住嘴的话
If you stop talking.
呆着别动
Stay exactly where you are.
Will，请回答
Will, come in.
Henry？
Henry?
Helen…
Helen...
不要想传送
Do not even think about teleporting.
电磁护盾在封闭模式下一样有效
The em shield stays active in lockdown mode.
我没想逃跑
I have no intention of escaping.
真的？
Really?
我会为我的所作所为负责
I will answer for my actions.
别试探我的耐心，John
Don't try me, John.
我是认真的，Helen
I'm quite serious, Helen.
情况不同了
Something has changed.
停下
Stop!
如果可以的话，我很乐意帮忙
If you'll let me, I'd like to help.
住口
Stop talking.
跪下，举起手来
On your knees, hands where I can see them.
好了吧？
Better?
OK，坚持住，我马上找人来帮忙
Okay, just sit tight. We're going to get some help.
哥们，我这需要帮忙
Dude, I need help in here.
嗯，我知道，但你得先把我弄出去
Yeah, I know, but you got to get me in the room.
明白
Yeah, I know.
怎么搞的？
What the hell is going on?
哥们，我被完全挡在系统外了，这事严重了
Dude, I'm completely shut out. This is very serious.
不是吧
Come on.
所有撤销指令我都试过了，Will…
I've tried every override command I can. Will...
我开不了门
I have no control.
试试那个…
What about the, uh...
喂？
Hello?
测试？
Check?
没反应？
Nothing?
没反应
I got nothing.
哦，Will！
Oh, will!
嗯，我知道
Yeah, I know.
坚持住
[Henry]: Hang on.
Magnus？
Magnus?
Kate？
Kate?
谁都行！
Anyone!
唉，这玩笑开大了
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
喂，监视系统被激活了
Hey, surveillance feed.
那儿
There.
谁能告诉我这儿到底怎么啦？
Will somebody please tell me what the hell is going on here?
黑暗，到处都是…
她说的话是什么意思？
gunama, what's that mean?
哇哦…
Wow...
我还不知道你是个技术奇才
I had no idea you were a techno whiz.
不知为什么
Don't know why.
那这房子有多老了？
So how old is this building?
我搬进来时电梯还是新的
Elevator was new when I moved in.
那是什么时候，1950年？
When was that, 1950?
51年
'51.
给，拿着这个
Here, hold this.
喂
Hello.
喂！
Hello!
大个子？
Big guy?
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
电梯里
In an elevator.
我知道，但具体在哪儿？
No, I know, but where are you?
Will…
Will...
是最初的电话系统
It's the original room-to-room intercom.
伙计，难以置信那东西还能用
Man, I can't believe that thing still works.
喂？
Hello?
嘿！
Hey!
到底怎么回事？
What's going on?
电话不通，所有装置都失灵了
The phones are dead. Nothing works.
嗯，我知道
[will]: Yeah, I know.
Henry跟一个病人锁在手术室里
Henry's locked in the or with a patient.
我被困在隔离间
I'm stuck on med level.
庇护所进入了古怪的封闭模式
We've gone into some weird lockdown mode.
为什么？
What for?
哦，我还指望你能告诉我呢
Well, I was hoping you could tell me.
什么地方故障了
Well, something's going down.
那也不该影响到电话，或把我们锁在系统外
Still, it shouldn't kill the phones, or lock us out of the computers.
至少我能看到你
At least I can see you.
监控系统还有效
You're on the surveillance cam.
Magnus跟Druitt锁在一块
Magnus is locked in with Druitt.
她还好吧？
Is she all right?
嗯，还好
Yeah, she's fine.
他暂时平静下来了
He seems quiet for now.
等等
W-w-wait.
如果音频设备坏了，怎么视频还能用？
If audio's down, why is video still running?
所有系统不是全该一塌糊涂了？
I mean, shouldn't everything be fubar?
为什么我要用这个老古董跟你讲话？
Why am I talking to you on the oldest intercom ever made?
有道理
Good point.
你还能联系到谁吗？我们这儿需要帮忙
Look, can you connect with anybody? We need some help down here.
好吧，我试试看
All right, I'll give it a shot.
好了吗？
We good?
还是被锁在系统外
We're still locked out.
哦，该死
Oh, come on.
这事确实跟我无关
This really is none of my doing.
不然我怎么会还在这儿？
Otherwise, why would I still be here?
不管是不是意外，你如果不老实我就开枪
Accidental or not, I will shoot you if you give me reason.
那是不错
That is very clear.
这完全没道理啊
None of this makes any sense.
封闭模式不该切断通信或干扰无线电、手机信号
Lockdown shouldn't cut off our communications or jam our radio and phone signals.
Henry的撤销指令肯定无效
Henry's overrides must not be working.
Helen，我知道时机不对，但你要了解
Helen, I know there's no good time, But I need you to understand something.
了解什么
What is this?
我的一部分就好像已经分离了
It's as if a part of me has been severed.
有人听得到吗？
Can anybody hear me?
是，我能，你在哪儿？
Yes, I can. Where are you?
电梯里
Elevator.
安全系统故障了
There's been a malfunction in the security system.
我需要协助
I need assistance.
其他人也需要
Not the only one.
不对，试试那条黑线
No, no. Try that one, the black wire.
Henry？Will？联系上她了
Henry? Will? Found her.
好的，最好把信号接过来
All right, boost the signal if you can.
你们连上了
You're connected.
Magnus，我们这儿有个重症伤患
Magnus, we got a patient In major distress here.
你们在哪儿？
Where are you?
跟Henry都在手术室，是Musa，她开始抽搐了
In the o.R. With Henry. It's Musa. She's having a seizure.
博士，她的心率飞快，但血压很低
[Henry]: Doc, her heart rate is rapid, but her blood pressure's really low.
我对她的状况了解不足
I don't know enough about her physiology.
下面要怎么做？
How do we proceed?
首先要制止抽搐
First priority, stop the seizure.
能找到镇静剂吗？
Can you find a vial of diazepam?
哦，好，好
Uh, yeah, yeah.
后面的柜橱里，左边底部
Back cabinets, bottom left.
静脉注射两毫克，没问题吧？
Two milligrams in an iv. Can you set that up?
是，没问题
Yeah, we're on it.
很好，注射完告诉我
Good. Let me know when that's up and running.
好的
All right.
那应该能制止抽搐了
It should calm her convulsions.
啊，现在要注射了
I'm doing it now.
哦，哇
Oh, boy.
那到底怎么回事？
So, what the hell happened?
远程终端这边，能做的我都做了
[Henry]: I've already tried everything I can from a remote terminal.
相信我，这不是小故障
This isn't a glitch, believe me.
我们是被故意锁在系统外的
We're locked out on purpose.
你看，我们的联系都被切断了
You know, we're all cut off from each other,
但监控系统还在运转
But there's elements from the security system that are still active.
这肯定是被攻击了
It's got to be a targeted attack.
不，不可能
No. No way.
自从上次系统被入侵
Since we got hacked,
远程安全协议都加了三重冗余功能，绝不可能再被黑
Our remote security protocols all have triple redundancies now, it's totally not possible.
没发现封闭漏洞，没有数据泄露，还有奇怪的电压波动
And no perimeter breach detected, no data theft, and these odd power fluctuations?
嗯，我知道，这都不是远程入侵的特征
Yeah, I know. None of it matches the patterns of a remote hack.
而我们正处于非常不利的境地
And yet we're all at a perfect disadvantage.
OK，肯定是被什么袭击了
Okay, so we got hit by something.
理论上有什么解决办法？
Any theories on how to undo it?
你看，这一切都发生在Henry重启主系统后
You know, this all started right after Henry rebooted the entire system.
之前还挺正常的，然后…
Everything was fine, and then--
系统过载肯定破坏了自动控制指令
The system overloaded. It must've damaged the automated commands running the sanctuary.
监视摄像机都在运转
[Henry]: All the security cameras are working,
但我却没法进入自己做的系统
But I can't get into a system that I created.
就像是有谁在实时控制这些
It's like someone's running all this in real time.
你觉得这都是庇护所内的人搞的？
[will]: You think somebody's controlling things from inside the building?
嗯，是我们救的某个异形？
Yeah, one of the abnormals we rescued?
不可能
[Magnus]: Impossible.
这不是他们的作风，他们是来寻求庇护的
They're here seeking asylum, and it's not their way.
Helen…
Helen...
你救活我时…
When you revived me...
系统过载，能量激增
The overload. A massive energy surge.
是啊，被什么引起的？
[will]: Yeah, but from what?
我感觉不同了，我感觉…
I feel different. I feel...
净化，被净化了
Purged, purified.
是从你那儿来的
It came from you.
我想是这样
I think so.
Musa怎么样了？
How's Musa doing?
哦，已经停止抽搐，似乎稳定了
Uh, well, the convulsions have stopped. She seems to be stabilizing.
很好，Henry，把除颤器充电，输出调到最大
[Magnus]: Good. Henry, take the defib paddles and charge them to maximum.
好的
All right.
OK，最大输出，准备好了
Okay, max power, ready.
电击配电盘
[Magnus]: Juice the electrical panel.
刚才什么东西出来了…
Something just came out...
那是什么鬼东西？
What the hell was that?
不是庇护所里的人，是庇护所本身
It's not anyone inside the building, it's the building itself.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
有什么活的东西控制了庇护所
That something very much alive is in control of the sanctuary.
像是什么活的电流？
What, like as in an electrical being?
这一个看来有意识，甚至天赋异禀
This one appears sentient, Even natively intelligent.
它能想出办法把我们彼此隔离开
It's found a way to cut us all off from each other.
电压波动，那是它在适应新环境
[will]: The fluctuations. It's testing its new environment.
没错，要不了多久它就会全面控制庇护所
Exactly, and it won't be long before it has full control.
OK，暂停下
Okay, time out.
你们确定这东西有敌意？
Are you guys sure this thing is hostile?
它被困在这里
It's a trapped creature.
也许它只是想…
Maybe it'll just...
像是…随便闲逛、散散心
I don't know, hang out and chill.
它是狂暴、残忍、无情的
It's violent, remorseless, relentless.
不会束手就擒的
It won't give up ground without a fight.
把它想成我
Think of it as facing me.
它一旦控制了庇护所，就很难阻止了
Once it has full control of this facility, it will be unstoppable.
它能轻易扩展到整个城市甚至更远
It could easily spread to the city and beyond.
那我们怎么对付它？
[Kate]: So how do we fight it?
Henry，我们需要…
[Magnus]: Henry, we need--
防御协议，明白
The defense protocols. You got it, doc.
我只要把它传至主网络
I just need to be able to feed it into the network.
那可不容易
[Magnus]: Which won't be easy.
跟我讲讲
Fill me in.
能量生物跟病毒很像
Energy creatures often behave like viruses.
任何适宜侵入的宿主，都能被它们寄生
They forge a parasitic relationship with whatever host environment they can invade.
是啊，四年前
[Henry]: Yeah, about four years ago
一个这类生物侵入了我们的备用发电机
We had something like this caught in our back-up generators.
惹了不少麻烦，直到被我们赶出去
It caused a lot of craziness till we flushed it out.
你要怎么做？
How'd you do that?
这一个把我锁在系统外，不过…
Well, this one's got me locked out, but...
如果能切断主电源
You know, if we can restart the main power,
冷启动一下，我也许能重获控制权
Do a cold start, I might be able to gain control.
也就是要到底层关电源
Which means getting into the catacombs and shutting down the power.
这点我们能做到吗？
Which we can't do, can we?
嗯，必须想法完成
Well, we have to find a way.
Kate，你能从电梯顶上能爬到另一层吗？
Kate, can you get out through the top of your elevator, climb to a different floor?
早想到过，但某人不同意
I've already thought of that, but opinions are divided.
我不喜欢这主意，尤其我们的一举一动都被监视着
I don't like it, not with something monitoring our every move.
是啊，它正看着我们呢
[will]: Yeah, it's watching all of us,
真令人毛骨悚然
Which is kind of creepy.
得了吧，它不可能知道我们想做什么
[Kate]: Oh, come on, it can't know what we're up to.
所有人，想办法遮住摄像机，要尽量不动声色
All of you, knock out your security cameras, as politely as possible.
搞定了
All right, done.
Henry，你能登录网络吗？
[Magnus]: Henry, are you able to log onto the network?
能，但还是被锁在系统外
[Henry]: Yeah, but I'm totally locked out.
这就像在玩Xbox…却没有手柄
It's like playing xbox without my...Joystick.
好吧，继续试着入侵
All right, keep trying to hack in.
这个生物还在适应新环境，也许会有可乘之机
As the creature adjusts to its new environment, it may give you an opening.
好的，交给我了
All right, I'm on it.
Will，从你那儿能进入旧的通风管吗？
Will, do you have any access to the old duct system from where you are?
嗯，这儿应该有个入口
Uh... Yeah, I guess there must be.
你想要我怎么做？
Why, what are you thinking?
旧的空调系统已被废弃
[Magnus]: The old heating system's obsolete.
几年前我们换装了辐射空调
We switched to radiant years ago.
换言之，旧系统也许在活电流的视线之外，不错
Meaning it's probably outside of electro's field of vision. Nice.
下到底层，重启系统
Get down there, reboot the system.
应该能让我们重新控制部分区域
It should give us control of some of the key sections.
好的
All right.
Kate，你要从上面爬到另一层
[Magnus]: Kate... One of you should climb up to the next floor,
看是否有其他办法到底层
See if there's another way to the catacombs.
知道了
[Kate]: We're on it.
你确定？
Are you sure?
我也能爬上去
I can go.
不，我更轻
No. I'm lighter.
爬的更快
I'll get there faster.
那很好
Faster's good.
来，我来帮你
Here, I'll help you.
喂，手老实点，猿人
(ss:Wookiee是《星球大战》里的猿人)
Hey, watch where the hands go, wookiee.
喂，我想我找到入口了
Hey, I think I found a way in.
好，去吧，小心点
All right, you should go. Just be careful.
一会儿见
See you in a few.
你说你感觉…不同了
You said you feel... Different.
这是什么意思？
What do you mean by that?
我内心的黑暗…已经完全消失了
The darkness within me is gone... Completely.
不同于Tesla的电击折磨，那只是暂时缓和，而这次…
Far more than when Tesla shocked me. That was appeasement, but this...
这次是…内心的安宁
This is... So peaceful.
这变化肯定是我救活你时发生的
It must have happened when I restarted your heart.
那生物自己从你体内跳到设备里
The creature jumped from you into the facility itself.
但它最初是怎么侵入我体内的？
But how did it end up inside me in the first place?
我不记得在哪儿遇到过它
I have no recollection of ever encountering it before.
你未必有印象
You wouldn't have to.
天啊，其实也难怪
God, it actually makes sense.
每次传送，你的分子结构都会转化为纯能量
Every time you teleport, you convert your molecular structure to pure energy.
是的
Yes.
这生物可能趁你某次传送时附上你
The creature could have latched onto you during one of your jumps,
在你实体化时完成寄生
Integrated into your being when you re-materialized.
而现在，它的影响已经消失…
And now... That its influence is gone...
它是不是导致我嗜杀成性的罪魁祸首？
Is it not possible this entity was the sole cause of my bloodlust?
从我使用能力开始，它就一直在毒害我的灵魂
That it's been polluting my soul since I began using my power?
哦…
Oh...
我很想相信你，John
I want to believe you, John,
但把你的罪孽归咎于别的东西也太过牵强了
But it's far too easy to blame everything you've done on something else.
是
Yeah.
对
Right.
现在我的头脑如此…清醒
My mind is so... clear.
就像我们当初相遇时
As it was when we first met.
那东西就是我是戾气
That thing was my rage.
我很确定
I'm sure of it.
这里很危险！你能感觉到吗？黑暗在逐渐壮大
嘘，嘘，没事
Shh, shh, it's okay.
你在这很安全，没事的
You're okay here. You're okay.
它正在…制造毒气
哦，我听不懂你在说什么啊
Oh, I so don't understand what you're saying right now,
不过能看得出不是好事！
But I can tell it's not good!
是什么在困扰你…
Something's bugging you--
你是个神入者，那么…
You're an empath, and that's--
哦，天啊，等等，那是什么？
Oh, god. Hang on a sec, what the hell is that?
等等
Hang on.
博士？
Doc?
它在找什么东西！
It's looking for something!
它正在扫描我们的化学品目录
It's scanning our chemical directory.
它要怎么实际拿到那些化合物
How could it actually access those compounds?
利用辅助机械手，有这个可能
Using the robotic assist mechanism. It is possible.
它在找些什么？
What else could it be after?
哦，它也许只是清查库存
[Henry]: Well, it could just be doing an inventory diagnostic.
不知道，我还在扫描，试着突破封锁
I don't know, I'm still scanning. I'm trying to find a way to break in.
如果它的注意力转移到…
If it shifts focus for--
Henry？
Henry?
博士？
Doc?
电话装置坏了
We lost the intercom!
那就快修
So fix it!
John，它想要什么？
John, what's its agenda?
混乱、死亡、折磨
Chaos, death, suffering.
耳熟吗？
Sound familiar?
一旦它摸透了身处的环境
Once it learns everything it can about its environment,
暴戾就会升级
The violence will escalate.
到西海岸来吧，我们聚聚…
(ss:他在模仿《虎胆龙威1》里主角爬通风管时的台词)
[as bruce willis]: Come out to the coast, we'll get together, have a few laughs...
右边是东方…
Right is east...
是吗？
Right?
OK…
Okay...
好，好得很
All right, fine.
你想玩真的，我奉陪
You want to play, let's play.
开始了
Here we go.
再赢我一次
You zap me again,
我就杀了你
And I'll kill you...
无论如何
Somehow.
哈利路亚！
Hallelujah!
哦，伙计…
Oh, man...
哦，找到火炉了
Oh, found the furnace.
我还以为这通风管已经不用了
Thought these were out of commission.
废弃个屁
(ss:之前Magnus告诉他旧空调系统已被废弃)
Defunct, my ass.
哦，糟了
Oh, crap.
它想把我们都杀了
哦，不是吧，电梯也？
Oh, come on. Elevator, too?
请放松下！
A little slack, please!
哦，不妙
Oh, not good.
Kate！
Kate!
该死
Dammit.
快下来
Get down here!
闪开点！
Get out of the way!
电梯能动了
We've got power again.
是的，但无法控制
Yes, but no control.
总有麻烦事，是吧？
It's always something, isn't it?
跟他娘写交响乐似的
I'm writing a damn symphony here.
快点…
Come on...
就那么点指令
Just a tiny little command,
威胁不到你
Nothing to threaten you.
快点…
Come on...
快啊！
Come on!
好诶！
Yes!
吃我一招，小电流！这是我的地盘！
Suck it, electro! This is my town!
这东西有制动器，对吧？
This thing has brakes, right?
以前有！
Used to!
下一个，电梯
Next, elevators.
对了，紧急制动装置…激活！OK！
Right, emergency brakes are... Active! Okay!
看吧，我说什么来着？
See? See? What'd I say?
OK，还有什么要我处理的，兄弟？
Okay, what else you got for me, buddy?
哦，不会吧
Oh, no.
他准备把我们都杀光
It's going to kill us all.
我说起过我讨厌骑马吗？
Did I mention I hate rides?
啊，还来？
Uh, really?
它在破坏制动器
It's stripping the emergency brakes.
还不断升高电梯，直到最顶端，然后…
And taking us higher, so that when we reach the top...
自由落体
We drop.
狗娘养的…
Oh, you son of a...
快点，Will，切断电源
Come on, Will, cut the power.
哈
Huh?
好啊
Yebo.
真是好啊
Yebo , damn right!
我想你的人已经解决问题了
I believe your people have risen to the occasion.
那是当然
Of course they have.
喂，博士，我是Henry
Hey, doc, it's Henry.
Will搞定了
Will did it.
通讯系统恢复了，其他的大部分也正常了
Communications are back, so's most of everything else.
大部分？
[Magnus]: Most?
是的，我正在处理剩下的
Yeah, I'm working on it.
博士，它要找的是毒素
Doc, the toxins it was scanning?
它在做毒性很大、扩散迅速的东西
It's making something very bad, very fast.
利用辅助机械手
It's using the automated assist.
你能撤销吗？
Can you override it?
嗯，不好办
Yeah, that's the problem.
我恢复了其他系统
I've reclaimed everything else,
但仍被锁在主实验室外
But I'm still locked out of the main lab.
我无法制止它
I can't make it stop.
Foss先生，能开开门吗？
Mr. Foss, can you open the door?
博士？
Uh, doc?
没事的，Henry
It's all right, Henry.
好的，稍等
All right, hang on.
好疼
Uh, ouch.
很好
Nice.
沙林神经毒气
Sarin gas nerve agent.
还有90秒，它就会从通风口释放毒气
We've got about 90 seconds. It'll release the compound into the vents.
它不会就此罢手的
It won't end here.
它会继续壮大，竭力毁灭一切、永不停止杀戮
It will grow, consuming whatever it can and never stop killing.
Henry，我们需要时间
Henry, we need more time.
没时间了
We don't have it.
OK，电源重启，我们应该没问题了
[will]: Okay, power's been reset. We should be good.
又怎么了？
What's happening now?
我的身体曾被它寄生
My entire body is geared to being its home.
让我去
Let me go.
John，你不必这么做，我们能想办法…
John, you don't have to do this. We could find a way--
我爱你
I love you.
永远铭记这点
Remember that... Always.
Foss先生
Mr. Foss,
劳驾你解除电磁护盾
Would you be so kind as to deactivate The em shield?
至死不渝
For all eternity.
拿急救包来！
I need a med kit right away!
离我远点！
Get away from me!
请让我帮帮你吧！
Please, let me help you!
我不要你帮忙！
I don't need your help!
如果不是你的话，它杀的人会更多
It would have killed a lot more if it weren't for you.
你一直在牵制它
You kept it at bay.
我要离开了
I need to leave now.
要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我也不知要去哪儿
I have no destination in mind.
John，等等
John, wait.
――――――――――――――――――
syjhsh翻译, 不当之处请多见谅
本字幕制作纯属个人兴趣
仅供学习交流, 严禁用于商业用途
――――――――――――――――――